Martha McNeil Hamilton Collection 089
People's Archive, MLK Library
Martha McNeil Hamilton Collection
1971-1997
People's Archive, MLK Library
Hamilton, Martha McNeil
089
1 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
Martha McNeil Hamilton was born in Houston, Texas on December 21, 1945 to Bruce and Evelyn Sims McNeil. She attended the University of Texas and received a BA in History. Prior to her career with the Washington Post, Hamilton worked for the Newark News, The Machinist, and the Journal of Commerce. She also spent some time as a reporter in Buenos Aires, Argentina. Hamilton is the author of the books The Great American Grain Robbery (1972) and Black and White and Red All Over (2002). She is the recipient of numerous awards, including the Front Page Award, 1978; the National Endowment for the Humanities Fellowship, 1978; the Duke Fellowship, 1986; and the Eisenhower Association Fellowship, 1995.
Custodial History
Martha McNeil Hamilton donated the materials to the DC Public Library in July 1996.
Related Materials
Collection #OHP018: Home Rule Oral History Project Collection #055: Home Rule Committee Collection Collection #003: Self-Determination for DC (SDDC) Collection Collection #OHP013: Milepost to Self-Govenment Oral History Project
Scope and Contents
This collection contains Washington Post reporter Martha McNeil Hamilton's research notes and articles pertaining to the fight for D.C. home rule, as well as related items such as reports, clippings, government documents, hearing transcripts, correspondence and election results.
Journalists; Women; Home rule -- Washington (D.C.); Reporters and reporting; Journalism
- Series 1
  - Clippings, 1973-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Record, October 4 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - DC Bar Board of Governor's Resolution, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Elections - General Election Results, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Elections - General Election Results, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Elections - General Election Results, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Elections - Primary Results, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Elections - Primary Results, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Home Rule - Articles, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Home Rule - Bills, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Home Rule - Bills, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Home Rule - Bills, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Home Rule - Bills, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Home Rule - Bills, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Home Rule - Bills, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Home Rule - Bills, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Home Rule - Walter Fauntroy, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Home Rule - General, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Home Rule - Statements, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Testimony, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Testimony, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Testimony, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Testimony, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Testimony, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Testimony, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Testimony, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Presidential Statements, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Reporter's Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Reporter's Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Reporter's Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Reporter's Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Statehood, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)